<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!--this will include all the strings used in the application, 
and also all the sql squries which are used to create the 
database file.-->

<resources>
    <string name="hello">Hello World, welcome!</string>
    <string name="app_name">Guide My Tour</string>
    <string name="GMT_onCreate">"
    CREATE TABLE beach (_id INTEGER, beachname TEXT, beachdiscription TEXT,img BLOB,latitude DOUBLE, longitude DOUBLE);
    CREATE TABLE hotel (_id INTEGER, hotelname TEXT, hoteldiscription TEXT,img BLOB,latitude DOUBLE, longitude DOUBLE);
    CREATE TABLE park (_id INTEGER, parkname TEXT, parkdiscription TEXT,img BLOB,latitude DOUBLE, longitude DOUBLE);
    CREATE TABLE waterfall (_id INTEGER, waterfallname TEXT, waterfalldiscription TEXT,img BLOB,latitude DOUBLE, longitude DOUBLE);
    CREATE TABLE mountain (_id INTEGER, mountainname TEXT, mountaindiscription TEXT,img BLOB,latitude DOUBLE, longitude DOUBLE);
    CREATE TABLE birdwatching (_id INTEGER, birdname TEXT, birddiscription TEXT,img BLOB,latitude DOUBLE, longitude DOUBLE);
    CREATE TABLE garden (_id INTEGER, gardenname TEXT, gardendiscription TEXT,img BLOB,latitude DOUBLE, longitude DOUBLE);
    CREATE TABLE test1 (_id INTEGER, name TEXT, discription TEXT,img BLOB,latitude DOUBLE, longitude DOUBLE);
    CREATE TABLE test2 (_id INTEGER, name TEXT, discription TEXT,img BLOB,latitude DOUBLE, longitude DOUBLE);
    INSERT INTO beach (_id ,beachname ,beachdiscription) VALUES (1,'Bentota', 'Bentota beach is one of the best beaches in the west coast, which has he added advantage of the Bentota ganga. Both the beach and the river is ideal for water sports.'); 
    INSERT INTO beach (_id ,beachname ,beachdiscription) VALUES (2,'Beruwala','56 km south of Colombo, Beruwela marks the beginning of a 130 km. stretch of beach where resort development has taken immense strides in the past few years. Good bathing may be had in the bay all year round.'); 
    INSERT INTO beach (_id ,beachname ,beachdiscription) VALUES (3,'Negombo','Negombo boasts of Sri Lankas first beach resort. The beach north of the town is a narrow and long. There are plenty of beachside restaurants and hotels for reasonable fees, and many a traveler make Negombo their last stop in Sri Lanka before flying out as it is the closest beach to the Air port.'); 
    INSERT INTO beach (_id ,beachname ,beachdiscription) VALUES (4,'Mount Lavinia','Just 12 km. south of Colombo, Mount Lavinia is an immediate city suburb and the beach is one of the better known even in colonial times. It lies alongside a wind swept headland jutting into the waters of the Indian Ocean. The sand is the softest and the waves calm and clear. The Governors House built in 1805 by Sir Thomas Maitland, now forms part of the famous Mount Lavinia Hotel.'); 
    INSERT INTO beach (_id ,beachname ,beachdiscription) VALUES (5,'Hikkaduwa','98 km. south of Colombo, Hikkaduwa is the place for underwater delight. Site of the famed coral gardens; hire a glass bottomed boat or goggles and flippers and explore the fantasies under your feet.'); 
    INSERT INTO beach (_id ,beachname ,beachdiscription) VALUES (6,'Unawatuna','About 5 km south of Galle is the golden beach of Unawatuna. It is also one of the safest beaches in Sri Lanka as it is protected by a reef. Surfing, snorkeling and diving are some of the water sports you can participate here. All the equipment you need can be rented from many a beachfront place.'); 
    INSERT INTO beach (_id ,beachname ,beachdiscription) VALUES (7,'Arugam Bay','14 km. from Colombo, a most beautiful bay with good surfing. The East coast offers infinite possibilities for all kinds of water sports and underwater photography. The many ship-wrecks of the coast are a tempting challenge to the diver.');
    INSERT INTO beach (_id ,beachname ,beachdiscription) VALUES (8,'Nilaveli Beach','4 km. from Trincomalee, Nilaveli was the venue for the 1985 International Funboard Championships.The beach has ample water sports facilities including fishing and sea angling. Whale watching in the sanctuary is a speciality. Pigeon Island, a ten-minute boat ride from the Nilaveli beach, is an ideal place to skin/scuba dive, or to just have a sun bath. A few metres from the coast is a small rocky island good for snorkeling.');
	INSERT INTO beach (_id ,beachname ,beachdiscription) VALUES (9,'Unawatuna Beach','Unawatuna beach is near Galle which is a beautiful wide curving golden beach. The beach has been acclaimed amongst 12 best beaches in the world. There is a reef protecting the beach, which makes it safe for bathing. Rumasssala, a rocky outcrop projecting into the sea at Unawatuna is connected to the legend of Ramayana. It is believed to be a piece of mountain that was fallen when Lord Hanuman brought the mountain to Sri Lanka in search of a medicinal herb to treat Laxamana-Ramas brother wounded in battle. The serene surroundings and the Dutch architecture add to the charm of the place.');
	INSERT INTO beach (_id ,beachname ,beachdiscription) VALUES (10,'Batticaloa Beach','District: Batticaloa Typical Weather is Warm and Sunny destination is 14 km from Colombo, Batticaloa is famous for its singing fish and picturesque lagoon.');
	INSERT INTO hotel (_id, hotelname, hoteldiscription) VALUES (1,'Mount Lavinia','Mount Lavinia Hotel invites you to walk into an Era of Colonial Splendor and Romance. Offering the best facilities of the modern world, this beachfront hotel is a legacy to the romance between a beautiful mestizo dancer, Lovina and the British Governor general of Ceylon, Sir Thomas Maitland. Hence this hotel has been famous for weddings and romantic getaways. Guests can enjoy the ambiance of the Victorian Era with meals prepared by world class chefs and the best service....');	
INSERT INTO hotel (_id, hotelname, hoteldiscription) VALUES (2,'Palm Beach','Palm Beach Hotel which is located in Mount Lavinia is a deluxe semi boutique type hotel which is about a 1 1/2 hour drive away from the International Airport. The Ratmalana Domestic Airport is also of proximity to Palm Beach Hotel. With 43 guestrooms offering modern amenities and comfortable settings, the hotel also provides a range of sumptuous menus for guests to savour from. Ideal for special functions such as weddings and corporate events, the management....');
INSERT INTO hotel (_id, hotelname, hoteldiscription) VALUES (3,'Bentota WaterSide','Recently opened, this popular a la carte Riverside Restaurant and hotel is fast becoming the place to be seen and dine in Bentota. Our six bed-roomed luxury hotel has been upgraded to Boutique Villa by the Sri Lankan Tourist Board because of the high standard of the rooms and the service. The tranquil location is unique amongst the palm trees and the rural village life. There are outstanding views from all the rooms, and in particular from the rooftop bar, from where you can watch spectacular....');
INSERT INTO hotel (_id, hotelname, hoteldiscription) VALUES (4,'Hotel Serendib','Located in Bentota which is famous for its beautiful beaches, Hotel Serendib provides guests a memorable holiday experience. With colourful interiors to suit your holiday mood complimenting your bedrooms, with a range of modern amenities, Hotel Serendib also offers delightful local and continental cuisine. From lazing around the pool to enjoying water sports in the vicinity of the premises, guests can have pure fun at Hotel....');
INSERT INTO hotel (_id, hotelname, hoteldiscription) VALUES (5,'Ceylon Continental','Ceylon Continental Hotel catering to both Business and leisure travelers, is ideally located in Colombo with easy access to many locations that are significantly important and offering a magnificent view of the Indian Ocean. Offering guests a 5 star experience the hotel provides a comfortable and luxurious atmosphere ensuring a memorable stay in the bustling city. Opened to the public in 1973, Ceylon Continental Hotel was refurbished in....');
INSERT INTO hotel (_id, hotelname, hoteldiscription) VALUES (6,'Cinnamon Grand','A place where senses are delighted and desires indulged - Cinnamon Grand Hotel is a venue of colours, sounds and unexpected pleasures. A perfect haven for holiday makers and business clients, the hotel is nestled in the commercial hub of Colombo. Luxurious rooms and elegant restaurants with excellent services are up for grabs at the hotel. Catering too both business and leisure, the hotel provides a range of facilities to make your stay memorable.');
INSERT INTO hotel (_id, hotelname, hoteldiscription) VALUES (7,'Concord Hotel','Concord Hotel Colombo was newly refurbished in 2010 to 3 star luxury standards, it is a deluxe luxury hotel located on the main Galle Road, only 10-15 minutes drive either to Colombo City Center, or the famous Mount Lavinia Beach. Great location, great hotel, very low prices, stay with us the next time youre in Colombo');
INSERT INTO hotel (_id, hotelname, hoteldiscription) VALUES (8,'Hilton Colombo','Hilton Colombo, a luxury Sri Lanka hotel is located right next to Colombo World Trade Center, the foremost landmark building in Colombo, the capital city of Sri Lanka. While Hilton Colombo is directly linked to the Colombo World Trade Center via a walkway, the Central Bank of Sri Lanka is just a stone’s throw away from the hotel. Colombo city center being the hub of business and commerce in Sri Lanka, most of the main Banks of Colombo are within walking distance from....');
INSERT INTO hotel (_id, hotelname, hoteldiscription) VALUES (9,'Galadari Hotel','Galadari Hotel that overlooks the vast Indian Ocean provides guests with a range of rooms and suites along with a very comprehensive list of facilities to enjoy their stay in Sri Lanka. The hotel which is able to cater to the requirements of both business and family travelers is specially geared to handle the needs of Muslim clients. Step into a world of elegance and royalty at the Galadari Hotel where you are provided with excellent services and....');
INSERT INTO hotel (_id, hotelname, hoteldiscription) VALUES (10,'Ramada Colombo','Nestled in the main commercial city of Colombo Ramada Colombo, recently refurbished, is all about exotic ambience and true Sri Lankan hospitality. Whether its for business or for pleasure, Ramada Colombo will cater to your every need.');
INSERT INTO hotel (_id, hotelname, hoteldiscription) VALUES (11,'Taj Samudra','The grand and magnificent Taj Samudra hotel offers you 5 star luxury and comfort. Although conveniently located in the citys business hub amidst the hustle and bustle of city life, it sits in the midst of 4 hectares of beautiful garden and soothing water fountains.');
INSERT INTO hotel (_id, hotelname, hoteldiscription) VALUES (12,'Galle Fort Hotel','The winner of Sri Lankas Leading Boutique Hotel award in the 2010 World Travel Awards, the Galle Fort Hotel is one of the best boutique hotels in Sri Lanka. Located in the Southern Province, this hotel offers a mix of elegant rooms and enormous suites all that are individually designed with tasteful neo-colonial decor and personal touches. The hotel owners manage the property well and offers superb food and the friendly staff and serene atmosphere helps you have a wonderful time');
INSERT INTO hotel (_id, hotelname, hoteldiscription) VALUES (13,'Mandalay','Mandalay was designed in consultation with Sri Lankas greatest architect Geoffrey Bawa, this luxury villa sits on the shore of the tranquil Lake Koggala. Positioned in a quiet Buddhist village next to a historic Temple, directly across from the Island of Madol Doova and only a quick stroll to the beach. It is 10 minutes south of the Galle Fort, and 10 minutes north of Welligama and only 5 minutes from some of the best restaurants and spas.');    
    "</string>
    <string name="GMT_onUpgrade">"
	DROP TABLE IF EXISTS beach
	DROP TABLE IF EXISTS hotel
	DROP TABLE IF EXISTS park
	DROP TABLE IF EXISTS waterfall
	DROP TABLE IF EXISTS birdwatching
	DROP TABLE IF EXISTS garden
	"</string>
	 <string name="GMT_Modify">"
 	CREATE TABLE waterfall (_id INTEGER, waterfallname TEXT, waterfalldiscription TEXT,img BLOB,latitude DOUBLE, longitude DOUBLE);
    CREATE TABLE mountain (_id INTEGER, mountainname TEXT, mountaindiscription TEXT,img BLOB,latitude DOUBLE, longitude DOUBLE);
    CREATE TABLE birdwatching (_id INTEGER, birdname TEXT, birddiscription TEXT,img BLOB,latitude DOUBLE, longitude DOUBLE);
    CREATE TABLE garden (_id INTEGER, gardenname TEXT, gardendiscription TEXT,img BLOB,latitude DOUBLE, longitude DOUBLE);
	"</string>
</resources>
